Guide to the Henry Lewis Stimson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Printed Material, 1884-1949; Series X
  - Printed Material, 1926, 1927-28, 1929, 1930, 1931-32 (Box 255)
  - Printed Material, 1933-34, 1935, 1936, 1937-38 (Box 256)
  - Printed Material, 1939, 1940-43, 1944-45, 1946 (Box 257)
  - Printed Material, 1947-48, 1949 (Box 258)
- Newspaper Clippings, Series XI
  - Newspaper clippings, 1889-1910 (Box 259)
  - Two scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, 1911-1913 (Box 259)
  - Clippings from guernatorial campaign, 1910 (Box 259A)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1911-1919 (Box 260)
  - Book of newspaper clippings on Constitutional Convention, 1915 (Box 260)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1920-1927 (Box 261)
  - Books of newspaper-clippings re: Nicaragua, 1927 (Box 262)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1928 (Box 263)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1929-30 (Box 264)
  - Three volumes of newspaper clippings re: 1930 London Naval Conference (Box 265)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1931-1932 (Box 265)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1933-37, 1938-39, 1940-52 (Box 266)
- Business, Financial and Legal Papers, 1893-1950; Series XII
  - Business, financial and legal papers, 1893-1946 (Box 267)
  - Business, financial and legal papers, 1944-1950 (Box 268)
  - Business, financial and legal papers: Maps and blueprints; Annotated material re: United States Army, 77th Division, 1923-1927 (Box 269)
- Photographs, Series XIII
  - Henry Lewis Stimson
    - 1872-1888 (Box 270, Folder 1)
    - 1917-1919 (Box 270, Folder 2)
    - 1920-1929 (Box 270, Folder 3)
    - 1930-1939 (Box 270, Folder 4)
    - 1940-1949 (Box 270, Folder 5)
    - undated (Box 270, Folder 6)
  - Family
    - Henry Lewis Stimson and Mabel Stimson (White), 1911-1945 (Box 271, Folder 7)
    - H.L. Stimson with members of Stimson and Wheeler families; Lewis and Candace (Wheeler) Stimson; Lewis and Candace Catherine Stimson, 1868-1869; circa 1860; undated (Box 271, Folder 8)
    - Mabel Wellington (White) Stimson, 1918-1934; undated (Box 271, Folder 9)
    - Candace Catherine Stimson, 1874-1889; undated (Box 271, Folder 10)
    - Candace (Wheeler) Stimson (Box 271, Folder 11)
    - Lewis Atterbury Stimson, 1861-1901; undated (Box 271, Folder 12)
    - Candace (Thurber) Wheeler, 1865; 1873; undated (Box 271, Folder 13)
    - Thomas Mason Wheeler; Dora (Wheeler) Keith, 1868; undated (Box 271, Folder 14)
  - Album of a vacation in the Rocky Mountains, undated (Box 272, Folder 15)
  - Hunting and fishing trips, 1886-1907; undated (Box 272, Folder 16)
  - Homes and office, Undated (Box 272, Folder 17)
  - Album of the yacht Fleur de Lys, circa 1905 (Box 273, Folder 18)
  - Fleur de Lys, 1890-1907; undated (Box 273, Folder 19)
  - Fleur de Lys, 1895; 1907; undated (Box 274–276)
  - Henry Lewis Stimson with others
    - 1880-1891 (Box 277, Folder 20)
    - 1910-1929 (Box 277, Folder 21)
    - 1930 (Box 277, Folder 22)
    - 1931 (Box 277, Folder 23)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 277, Folder 24)
    - 1940-1943 (Box 277, Folder 25)
    - 1944 (Box 277, Folder 26)
    - 1945 (Box 277, Folder 27)
    - Award of Distinguished Service Medal to H.L.S., 1945 September 21 (Box 277, Folder 28)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 277, Folder 29)
    - undated (Box 277, Folder 30)
  - H. L. Stimson as Secretary of War, visiting the Fifth Army in Italy, 1944 (Box 278–279)
  - H. L. Stimson as Secretary of War, in England, 1944 (Box 280)
  - Panama Canal construction, 1904-1912 (Box 281–282)
  - Wreck of the U.S.S. Maine, 1911 (Box 283)
  - Nicaragua, 1927 (Box 284, Folder 31)
  - Galapagos Islands, 1941 (Box 284, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of others (Box 284, Folder 33-34)
  - Buildings and submarine named for Stimson, circa 1960 (Box 284, Folder 35)
  - Unidentified, Undated (Box 284, Folder 36)
  - Oversize photographs (Box 285)
  - Scrapbooks of newspaper clippings pertaining to Philippines, 1928 April - 1929 February (Box 286)
  - Drawing for bookplate for Candace C. Stimson, Undated (Box 286)
- Diaries, 1909-1945; Series XIV
  - Original Volumes, 1909-1945
    - v.1 - v.7, 1909 January 17 - 1927 -MayApril (Box 69)
    - v.7 - v.10, 1927 May 10 - 1930 December 31 (Box 70)
    - v.11 State Department statements and letters, 1929 - 1933 (Box 70)
    - v.12 - v.17, 1930 January 17 - 1931 August 27 (Box 71)
    - v.18 - v.23, 1931 September - 1932 October 3 (Box 72)
    - v.24 - v.30, 1932 October 4 - 1940 September 30 (Box 73)
    - v.31 - v.36, 1940 October 1 - 1941 December 31 (Box 74)
    - v.37 - v.42, 1942 January 1 - 1943 April 30 (Box 75)
    - v.43 - v.48, 1943 May 1 - 1944 October 31 (Box 76)
    - v.49 -v.52, 1944 November 1 - 1945 September 21 (Box 77)
  - Copy-flow volumes
    - v.1 - v.2, 1909 (Box 1)
    - v.2- v.3, 1911 May 13 - 1919 January 8 (Box 2)
    - v.3 - v.4, 1919 February 2 - 1920 February 1 (Box 3)
    - v.4 - v.5, 1917 December 19 - 1918 August 12 (Box 4)
    - v.5 - v.7, 1919 January 25 - 1927 April 19 (Box 5)
    - v.6A - v.9, 1926 June 29-1926 October 3; 1928 October 2-1928 November 28 (Box 6)
    - v.7, 1927 April 19 - 1927 May 19 (Box 7)
    - v.8, 1928 February 29 - 1928 July 31 (Box 8)
    - v.8 and Index - v.6A + 9-13, 1928 August 3 - 1928 September 28 (Box 9)
    - v.9 - v.10, 1928 November 19 - 1930 October 2 (Box 10)
    - v.10, 1930 October 2 - 1930 December 5 (Box 11)
    - v.10 - v.11, 1930 December 6 - 1930 December 31 (Box 12)
    - v.11, 1930 June 6 - 1933 March 3 (Box 13)
    - v.12, 1930 January 17 - 1930 February 8 (Box 14)
    - v.13, 1930 February 9 - 1930 March 7 (Box 15)
    - v.13 and Index - v.14-18, 1930 March 7 - 1930 March 21 (Box 16)
    - v.14 - v.15, 1930 March 22 - 1931 February 13 (Box 17)
    - v.15, 1931 February 14 - 1931 April 19 (Box 18)
    - v.16, 1931 April 20 - 1931 June 11 (Box 19)
    - v.16-v.17, 1931 June -1931 June18 (Box 20)
    - v.17 -v.18, 1931 July 20 - 1931 September 18 (Box 21)
    - v.18, 1931 September 19 - 1931 October 31 (Box 22)
    - v.19 and Index, 1931 November 1 - 1931 November 27 (Box 23)
    - v.19 - v.20, 1931 November 28 - 1932 January 8 (Box 24)
    - v.20, 1932 January 9 - 1932 February 14 (Box 25)
    - v.20 - v.21, 1932 February 15 - 1932 April 7 (Box 26)
    - v.21 - v.22, 1932 April 18 - 1932 June 3 (Box 27)
    - v.22 - v.23, 1932 June 4 - 1932 July 14 (Box 28)
    - v.23, 1932 July 15 - 1932 October 3 (Box 29)
    - Index v.24-28 + v.24, 1932 October 4 - 1932 November 2 (Box 30)
    - v.24, 1932 November 3 - 1932 December 15 (Box 31)
    - v.25, 1932 December 15 - 1933 January 19 (Box 32)
    - V.25 - V.26, 1933 January 20 - 1933 February 19 (Box 33)
    - v.26, 1933 February 20 - 1933 October 26 (Box 34)
    - v.27, 1933 October 27 - 1935 May 4 (Box 35)
    - v.27 - v.28, 1935 May 6 - 1938 March 29 (Box 36)
    - v.28 and Index v.29 -v.34, 1938 March 31 - 1938 December 16 (Box 37)
    - v.29 - v.30, 1939 January - 1940 August 16 (Box 38)
    - v.30 -v.31, 1940 August 17 - 1940 October 9 (Box 39)
    - v.31, 1940 October 10 - 1940 November 30 (Box 40)
    - v.32, 1940 December 1 - 1941 January 31 (Box 41)
    - v.33, 1940 February 1 - 1941 April 5 (Box 42)
    - v.33 - v.34, 1941 April 6 - 1941 May 31 (Box 43)
    - v.34, 1941 June 1 - 1941 July 31 (Box 44)
    - Index v.35-40 + v.35, 1941 August 1 - 1941 September 15 (Box 45)
    - v.35 - v.36, 1941 September 16 - 1941 November 21 (Box 46)
    - v.36 -v.37, 1941 November 22 - 1942 January 13 (Box 47)
    - v.37 - v.38, 1942 January 14 - 1942 March 6 (Box 48)
    - v.38, 1942 March 7 - 1942 April 30 (Box 49)
    - v.39, 1942 May 1 - 1942 July 7 (Box 50)
    - v.39 - v.40, 1942 July 8 - 1942 September 18 (Box 51)
    - v.40 and Index v.41-46, 1942 September 19 - 1942 October 31 (Box 52)
    - v.41, 1942 November 1 - 1943 January 7 (Box 53)
    - v.41 - v.42, 1943 January 8 - 1943 March 12 (Box 54)
    - v.42 - v.43, 1943 March 13 - 1943 May 26 (Box 55)
    - v.43 - v.44, 1943 May 27 - 1943 July 4 (Box 56)
    - v.44, 1943 July 28 - 1943 October 21 (Box 57)
    - v.44 - v.45, 1943 October 22 - 1943 December 9 (Box 58)
    - v.45 - v.46, 1943 December 10 - 1944 March 5 (Box 59)
    - v.46, 1944 March 6 - 1944 April 30 (Box 60)
    - Index v.47-52 + v.47, 1944 May 1 - 1944 June 9 (Box 61)
    - v.47 - v.48, 1944 June 10 - 1944 September 4 (Box 62)
    - v.48, 1944 September 5 - 1944 October 31 (Box 63)
    - v.49, 1944 November 1 - 1944 December 31 (Box 64)
    - v.50, 1945 January 1 - 1945 February 26 (Box 65)
    - v.50 - v.51, 1945 February 27 - 1945 April 29 (Box 66)
    - v.51 - v.52, 1945 April 30 - 1945 July 15 (Box 67)
    - v.52, 1945 July 16 - 1945 September 21 (Box 68)
  - Alphabetical index by volume
    - Indices for volumes 1-52, 1909-1945 (Box 78, Folder 1-9)
- Additional Material, 1910; Accession 2010-M-033
  - Letters to Stimson from his wife, Mabel Wellington White Stimson, 1910 October 18, 19, 21 (Box 1, Folder 1)